DILLON WILLIAMS

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

CONTACT INFORMATION



615-785-9637



dillonwilliamsail@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/dillon-williams/



dillon-williams.com



github.com/CosignMyCodesign

PERSONAL SUMMARY

After working mostly in management for the majority of my career, I was constantly evaluating ways to improve differing business opportunities. I became known to come up with out-of-the-box ways of thinking that addressed company issues and was able to use my creative problem-solving ability to improve operations in a variety of ways. Growing up, I always had a particularly strong affinity for computers. I was enamored with what was going on behind the curtains and amazed by the endless capabilities. I've held onto that affection over the years and after experiencing multiple career opportunities, I realized I would never be truly satisfied until I was doing what I loved. With software development I can use both my inherent skill set of creative thinking and problem solving as well as my career-driven skills I've curated over time. I crave constant growth, and this career enables me to learn, and be challenged every day. After my time at NSS I can't imagine doing anything different, and I am beyond excited about what my future in this industry holds.

EDUCATIONAL HISTORY

Full Stack Development Bootcamp
Nashville Software School | 2018-2019

Journalism and Electronic MediaUniversity of Tennessee | 2009-2011

CAREER SUMMARY

Software Developer

Nashville Software School | 2018-Present

Intensive full-time 6-month software development boot camp focusing on full stack development fundamentals and problem solving. The final half of the program executed in a simulated company environment with Scrum methodology.

- Front-end primarily focused in Javascript and Reactjs.
- Back-end primarily focused in Python/Django/SQL.
- Single-page application development using ES6, Javascript and jQuery modular code bundled with Browserify and utilizing Grunt as a task runner for linting and bundling.
- Individual and group project management through issue tickets and Github projects with version control *via Git and Github*
- Application design through whiteboarding dependencies and database planning by building entity relationship diagrams to define data relationships.

Individual Projects

Squad Spawn | Front-End Capstone

Growing up, I spent countless hours researching my favorite athletes. It proved tedious to navigate between multiple websites and team pages/ rosters to find information about the player I was interested in. I created Spawn Squad to fill this void. With Spawn Squad a user can assemble a team of their favorite NBA players and easily navigate between player profiles, save notes about individual players, and also delete players from their squad if needed. It's quick, clean, and easy-to-use. My favorite thing about Squad Spawn is that it provides me endless room for improvement and added content/functionality in the future. It will be a one-stop website to view player information, statistics, videos, and news articles. Squad Spawn is a single-page responsive CRUD web application built in React.Js with Semantic UI React for styling and design. It utilizes a custom JSON database containing vast information about each player in the NBA.

https://github.com/CosignMyCodesign/Front-end_Capstone

Group Projects

Nutshell and React Nutshell | Front-End

Nutshell is a social media app giving a user the ability to add news articles, events, and a task-list, as well as chat with other users. The first version was written in vanilla Javascript while the second version was written in React. Both versions utilized modular programming, creation of ERDs for planning, and JSON server for persistent storage. I was in charge of the events components and involved in the task-list components. I also created the database and presented the projects for demonstration.

https://github.com/Team-Acornucopia/Nutshell https://github.com/Team-Acornucopia/Nutshell-React

(CAREER SUMMARY CONTINUED)

Academy Sports & Outdoors

Operations Manager | 2016-2018

- Managed teams of up to 20 employees at a time. Was in charge of hiring, training, and scheduling of employees in a specific department.
- Performed the on-boarding for all employees that were hired at the store. This included getting them integrated in all of our systems (SIM, PIM, Kronos, Controller Access), assigning the proper training modules for a given department, maintaining proper training requirements throughout their tenure (yearly firearm exams, quarterly safety training, etc).
- Trained and groomed Senior Leads and Team Leads to manage their teams as well as possible and provided guidance on how they
 could best improve the company as well as position themselves for future advancement.
- Met with management team on a weekly basis to strategize how we could improve certain areas of the store and also discuss any potential weaknesses to be addressed. Constant forward-thinking depending on the time of the year and what events. sports, tournaments, etc were occurring at the time to maximize revenue.
- Heavily involved in multiple weekly conference calls with managers from across the region and district as well as regional and district managers. Was expected to contribute to these calls in a variety of ways (coming up with creative merchandising opportunities, tracking sales of certain items and providing advice on how to improve, discussing potential realignment of certain departments/roles).

Senior Logistics Lead | 2015-2016

- Was in charge of shipping and receiving of product, ensuring all counts were correct, and keeping backstock efficiently organized.
- Led a team of 8 employees and coordinated with them to properly unload and load trucks, get product on the floor and in the appropriate spots, as well as train them in various areas in the store to fill in and help when needed.
- Came up with a new system of organization in the stock-room by consolidating and rotating palleted product more effectively, as well as redistributing store fixtures and ensuring we had the proper amounts to run the store as well as possible.
- Attended weekly conference calls with management of the 1.4 million sq. foot warehouse to maintain logistical integrity and to plan for and be aware of any upcoming changes.

American Income Life Insurance

Life Insurance Specialist | 2015

- Developed base for long-term sources of clients by using referrals, occupational, and special-interest groups to compile lists of prospects.
- Determined clients' particular needs and financial situations by scheduling appointments; determining extent of present coverage and investments; ascertaining long-term goals.
- Worked in excess of 60 hours weekly to ascertain I would hit all three bonus tiers for sales each week. Was the second leading salesman at my branch during my time with the company.

Toot's Restaurant

Manager | 2013-2015

- Helped run and maintain the busiest and highest-revenue restaurant in the Murfreesboro area starting at 20 years old. Personally engineered a new system of server/host/kitchen duties to handle the ever-increasing customer flow and maximize profitability, this method is still used to this day in all Toot's locations.
- Interviewed, hired, and trained over 100 employees in my time with the company.
- Handled customer-relations on a daily basis, including resolving conflicts and maximizing enjoyable experiences. Had to be able to quickly and effectively make decisions that always took care of the customer first and foremost.
- Constructed strategy-driven schedules for hosts and servers to ensure we had the proper employees in place in order to provide the best customer experience possible.
- Processed financial transactions after the close of business by calculating all revenue gained from the day and cross-checking expected income based on sales. Also processed daily deposits to the bank in the morning.

Server | 2011-2013

- Handled a wide-variety of customer interactions and always provided the best possible experience. I had the highest customer feedback score in our store for 2 years running.
- Had a full-section of customers on a nightly basis (up to and occasionally exceeding 40 customers at a time).
- Responsible for greeting customers, assisting in selection of food and drinks, answering all question regarding food preparation, sending the ticket to the kitchen properly explained, ensuring orders being brought to the table were correct, maintaining a beverage glass that never went below half, checking-out each customer, and cleaning and setting up the table for the next guests.